PERSONAL PARTICULARS

Availability for Employment: Immediate Last Drawn Salary: \$3000 basic salary Expected Salary: \$2,900 - \$3,000 basic salary

CAREER SUMMARY

Further accomplished profession with 9 years experience in Aviation Industry. Vast experience in performing warehouse management function in accordance with CAAS regulatory. Further 3 years experience in Marine Logistics and 6 years of experience as Customer Service Executive.

Offer outstanding team leadership, independent and initiative, proficiency to furnish reports and presentation.

Ability to coordinate with customers, cross-functional teams and forwarding agents with the direction of executing operational tasks smoothly.

SKILLS AND KNOWLEDGE

- Acquired knowledge on mechanical, electronic and computer engineering.
- Equipped with good interpersonal skills.
- Amiable, people-oriented person with enthusiasm for learning.
- An ability to follow instructions and work hand in hand as a team.
- Hard working and willing to learn.
- Well versed in Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint and Microsoft Office.
- Familiar with CITRIX, SAP and NAVISION system.
- Obtained forklift license.
- Versed in IATA Dangerous Goods declaration.
- Obtained fork-lift license (5 tonne).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

FREELANCE DELIVERY & APPAREL E-COMMERCE BUSINESS

PERIOD: MAY 2021 - PRESENT

- Develop a growth strategy focused both on financial gain and customer satisfaction
- Conduct research to identify new markets and customer needs
- Arrange business meetings with prospective clients
- Promote the products/services addressing or predicting clients' objectives & prepare sales transactions
- Provide trustworthy feedback and after-sales support
- Build long-term relationships with new and existing customers
- Delivering a wide variety of items
- Plan & follow delivery driving routes and time schedules
- Loading, unloading, preparing, inspecting delivery goods.
- Managing design process from conception through to final styling.
- Conducting market research to identify new trends, fabrics and techniques, and seeking design inspiration.
- Creating production sketches for development packages.
- Collaborating with technical designer to ensure development packages are accurate.

- Reviewing product for style and fit during presentation.
- Presenting story, mood, color boards, and samples to buyers.

SEAMAP PTE LTD

EMPLOYMENT PERIOD: JUL 2017 – MAY 2021 Reason for leaving: To look after unwell spouse diagnosed with bell palsy

Appointment:

Logistics Executive cum Customer Service (Supervisory Role)

- Responsible for overall warehouse stock movements such as receipt of incoming goods receipt, movements between warehouse (e.g. work orders, internal transfers) and sales orders deliveries. Preparing Sales Orders, Transfer Orders, RTV/RMA accurately and accordingly. Follow up with generating of shipping documents for despatch.
- Plan the effective use of both internal and external warehouse space through proper and efficient stock layout. Planning of required external packaging materials for despatch.
- Ensure inventory accuracy through prompt system updates and controls such as cycle and full stock counts.
- Manage and ensure stringent quality checks of products and quality reject process.
- Coach and guide beneficiaries to perform warehouse tasks.
- Assist in day-to-day retail store operations.
- Perform other admin tasks.
- Export coordination of air freight shipments.
- Preparing control Documents (Certificate of Origin, Certificate of Quality & Quantity etc.) for submission to AGC.
- Respond to phone, e-mail, or faxed and requests from customers, agents and sales representatives.
- Manage day-to-day repair administration and warranty operation.
- Provide sales and repair quotation accordingly to customer based on SEAMAP's policy.
- Handle bookings for consignee routed cargo as requested by customers. Coordinate pickups and provide timely quotes for sales.
- Obtaining estimated costs for cargo such as dangerous goods and perishables. Follow up on cargo arrival at destination for any arrangements.
- Manages and investigate discrepancies.

- Filing of the necessary documents for shipment tracking (Acknowledgement of receipts, cargo collect, delivery note, etc)
- Ensure shipments are in accordance with Seamap's policy and customer's shipping instructions.
- Update & maintain records of all inbound shipments, proforma invoice & drop shipment AWB details.
- Conduct yearly stock take and cycle counting.
- Monitor shelf-life controlled items and coordinate disposals of expired goods. Perform storing of Dangerous goods items.
- Coordinate inbound and outbound shipments to repair centre. Monitoring shipment status to update customers.

SATAIR PTE LTD

EMPLOYMENT PERIOD: JUN 2014 - JUN 2017 Reason for leaving: Looking for career enhancement and better prospect

Appointment:

Logistic Coordinator cum Customer Service for Airbus Avionics OEM F6198 C/O SATAIR PTE LTD

- Support all customer activities in APAC. Reporting directly to Regional Director of APAC for all activities. Establish and maintain communication with the stakeholders (local partners, foreign customers) on repair unit process status.
- Follow-up of repair activities in Singapore and monitor the performance of the repair stations. Liaise with Airbus Avionics Team (Sales, Technical and Finance) in Toulouse. France for repair activities in APAC.
- Manage day-to-day repair administration and warranty operation. Manage Repair management and review of AD/SB/SIL application on component.
- Provide sales and repair quotation accordingly to customer based on catalogue (New components and Repair capability lists)
- Management of the logistic procedure from the arrival of the components to the final delivery such as perform visual and quality inspection on components received adhere to airworthiness requirements. Ensure outbound shipment adhere to IATA DG requirement.
- Filing of the necessary documents for shipment tracking (Acknowledgement of receipts, cargo collect, delivery note, etc)
- Daily AOG After Office Hours standby duty
- Prepare weekly report of inventory, stock movements and repairs follow-up.

- Issuance of invoices and relevant shipping documents
- Ensure shipments are affected in accordance to Satair's policy and customer's shipping instructions
- Informing relevant sales functions/colleagues about potential deviations to agreed transport/shipping agreements.
- Control of and booking of freight invoices.
- Maintain contact with Satair's and customers' freight forwarders.
- Assist in investigating of short/over shipment & any other cases.
- Update & follow-up on Error Log cases.
- Update & maintain records of all inbound shipments, proforma invoice & drop shipment AWB details.

ST AEROSPACE SERVICES COMPANY PTE LTD

EMPLOYMENT PERIOD: MAY 2013 - MAY 2014

Reason for leaving: Better offer from SATAIR.

Appointment:

Quality Inspector (Supervisory Role)

- Inspect aircraft spares
- Verify aircraft spares to ensure appropriate accompanying documents from the OEMs, vendors and suppliers
- Work on continuous improvement projects to improve work areas & procedures
- Facilitate periodic audits from civil aviation authorities & customers
- Maintain Shelf Life records for aircraft spares with limited life
- Monitor and conduct surveillance audits on all stores activities within the Bonded Stores
- Raise Discrepancy Reports for any discrepancies found on any aircraft spares in the Bonded Stores

SINGAPORE HONGKONG AIRCRAFT ENGINEERING CO. PTE LTD

EMPLOYMENT PERIOD: JUL 2009 - MAY 2013

Reason for leaving: Retrenchment.

Appointment:

Warehouse Coordinator/Inspector

- Manage aircraft spares in accordance with CAAS SAR145. Ensure that the record meets the audit criteria.
- Coaching and guiding store team on problem solving with regards to logistics operational issues.
- Continuous implementation of work instructions and training to develop better process flow.
- Perform receiving inspection and update data in relevant systems.
- Analyzing inventory systems (MCS) problems such as discrepancies of spares.
- Conduct yearly stock take and cycle counting.
- Liaising with customers for their daily or urgent demands.
- Monitor shelf-life controlled items and coordinate disposals of expired goods.
- Coordinate inbound and outbound shipments to repair centre. Monitoring shipment status to update customers.
- Liaise with appointed agent for collection and delivery arrangements.
- Ensure proper documents storage for tracking purposes.
- Attained IATA Dangerous Goods declaration.

Education

2005 – 2007	Institute of Technical Education (College East, Tampines) Higher Nitec Cert in Mechatronics
2002-2005	Institute of Technical Education (College East, MacPherson) Nitec Cert in Mechatronics
	Bartley Secondary School Cambridge N' level – 7 credits
<u>Civil Service NSF (Completed)</u>	

Singapore Police Force (SPF) [June 2007 – Jul 2009]

Staff Admin to Commanding Officer (Toa Payoh NPC)

- Basic Administration
- Basic Data Entry
- Overall Deployment Officer of Toa Payoh NPC

Languages

Fluent in English and Malay (spoken and written)